VALERIO LUCANTONIO

Software Engineer

ABOUT

- Valerio Lucantonio
- 30 September 1989
- **1** L'Aquila, Italy
- Zurich, Switzerland

CONTACTS

- +41 76 222 71 92
- ✓ valerio.lucantonio@gmail.com
- waleriolucantonio.github.io
- in linkedin.com/in/valerio-lucantonio

LANGUAGES

Italian (native)

English (professional)

German (basic)

SUMMARY

I am a software engineer with 8+ years of technical expertise. For the last 6+ years I have been living in Zurich where working for companies of different sizes from big corporates to startups. I strive for high quality architecture design and agile processes. I bring a lot of experience in product design with particular attention to frontend and UX. I have a lot of energy and a strong educational background which makes me adapting quickly to new challenges and technologies.

JOB EXPERIENCES

Lead Frontend Engineer

AKENZA, ZURICH | MAR 2021 - PRESENT

Working on an IOT web application for MVP and after go-live

- Leading the frontend team on architecture and design topics
- Main point of contact for designer, product owner and BE devs.
- Set foundations for design system and technical documentation

Technologies: Angular 12, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3

Senior Full Stack Software Engineer (Contract)

CREDIT SUISSE, ZURICH | JAN 2021 - MAR 2021

Worked on several web applications in the area of wealth management

- Supported existing applications with maintenance
- Analysed existing technical depth to come up with a plan to reduce it
- Set foundations for the refactoring of one application

Technologies: Angular 10, AngularJs, Java, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3

Senior Frontend Engineer & Scrum Master

EVOOQ, ZURICH | SEP 2019 - JAN 2021

Worked on an ecosystem of web apps in the area of structure products trading and lifecycle management.

- Led frontend architecture and design of the ecosystem
- Set up scrum process for a cross functional team of 8 people
- Scrum master hosting dailies, plannings, groomings and retros
- Implemented MVP and supported clients in the after go-live phase
- Re-implemented existing complex form-based application

Technologies: Angular 8, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3, graphql, GRPC

VALERIO LUCANTONIO

Software Engineer

SKILLS

JavaScript Express.js **TypeScript Iasmine** Angular **Jenkins** Aurelia Webpack Ionic Selenium HTML **GIT** CSS SQL MongoDB JAVA

HOBBIES











JOB EXPERIENCES

Senior Frontend Engineer & Scrum Master

OPEN WEB TECHNOLOGY, ZURICH | JAN 2019 - SEP 2019

Worked on a B2C real estate app and a B2B incident reporting portal

- Led frontend architecture and design of real estate application
- Set up scrum process for a cross functional team of 6 people
- Scrum master hosting dailies, plannings, groomings and retros
- Supported features enhancements of existing reporting portal

Technologies: Aurelia, Angular 6, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3

Software Engineer

AVALOQ, ZURICH | NOV 2015 - JAN 2019

Worked on different apps part of a big e-banking ecosystem in the area of payment and trading.

- Worked on complex apps with customisation exposed to clients
- Implemented MVP and sent live more than 25 banks
- Re-implemented existing apps with stricter quality criteria
- Worked on full-stack end-to-end features

Technologies: AngularJs, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Java, SQL

Freelance Web Developer

FREELANCE | 2013 - PRESENT

Worked on different web based B2C small/medium size websites and mobile applications. The software vary in field, size and businesses: from personal websites, to company presentation portfolios, ecommerces, touristic and outdoor mobile applications.

Technologies: MEAN stack, Angular, Ionic, Backbone, Cordova, CMSs

EDUCATION

Master Degree in Software Engineering

UNIVERSITY OF L'AQUILA & MALARDALEN UNIVERSITY | 2013 - 2015

Part of an international program named Global Software Engineering European Master (GSEEM). The program was distributed between University of L'Aquila, Italy where I held 10 exams and Malardalen University, Sweden where I held 4 projects exams and the master thesis.

Bachelor Degree in Computer Science

UNIVERSITY OF L'AQUILA | 2008 - 2012

Studied Computer Science as a bachelor degree, at the University of L'Aquila. This course gives a solid theoretical background, and a wide techology overview.